## LUKE TYSON`

Fullstack Developer

(850) 206.8238 · <u>Luketyson17@gmail.com</u> · Santa Fe, NM · <u>linkedin</u> · <u>github</u>

#### SUMMARY

Software Engineer with a background in people - I have over 10 years of professional experience in customer-oriented roles and my undergraduate education consisted of a seminar-based curriculum founded on analysis and group-led, discussion-based approaches to learning materials. I excel in high-level technical conversations, and my skills shine when working with a team. My experience in service has made me highly empathetic not only to the needs of clients, but also to the needs of my colleagues. I cherish being able to ease the pains and augment the successes of my teammates.

### **SKILLS**

**Languages** - JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS | **Libraries and Frameworks** - React, Node.js, Express.js, Django **Database** - SQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, ORM, ODM | **Other** - RESTful Routing, APIs, JSON

### SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

February 2023 - Present

#### Jam | Full-stack web application | MERN

- Designed and created a web-based chat application with the MERN stack, going from initial set-up to deployment within the span of
  one week.
- Coded four database models utilizing Mongoose schemas, first designing their connections within an ERD, then implementing their relationships through reference keys, and accessing and manipulating them through RESTful API calls.
- Implemented socket connections on the backend through socket.io, weaving API calls into the socket listening and emission events to create a seamless data flow in tandem with the users' live-chatting experience.

### Slack Overflow | Full-stack web application | Python, Django

- Used Python with Django to design and create a full-stack web application with full create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations deployed through Heroku's cloud platform.
- Developed the application with specific use cases and general user experience in mind, and designed the layout with the goal of making an app that would be helpful to junior developers in my professional community.
- Ran daily SCRUM with a teammate utilizing kanban boards, wireframes, and ERDs to guide team workflow, visualize stylistic goals, and depict plans for data models.

### Netbuster | Full-stack web application | HTML, CSS, Express, Node.js

- Developed creative design plans with a teammate to create a video library styled as a Blockbuster streaming service.
- Implemented a MEN stack (MongoDB, Express, Node.js) to build a full stack application in a week with full create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations hitting all RESTful API calls.
- Used Mongoose to define schemas for MongoDB collections and styled the application using Styled-Components and CSS3 with flexbox layouts.

#### Snake | Desktop web game | HTML, CSS, JavaScript

- Wrote a functional algorithm utilizing JavaScript's DOM-manipulation capability to recreate the classic game, Snake.
- Designed a wireframe for the site through Figma and styled the webpage with CSS3.
- Deployed the game through Github pages and collected feedback from friends and acquaintances to troubleshoot in-game bugs.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

General Assembly, Software Engineering Fellow | Santa Fe, NM

February 2023 - May 2023

- Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies.
- Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

# Ten Thousand Waves, Guest Services Associate | Santa Fe, NM

June 2022 - January 2023

- Welcomed and guided tens of thousands of guests through orientation processes to learn the layout and systems of the spa and hotel.
- Utilized Booker software to make reservations for thousands of guests and helped guests to troubleshoot any errors that they
  encountered when using spa software.
- Apprenticed in the on-site woodshop to aid in the construction of an addition to the spa's restaurant, independently learning the maintenance and use of tools through supervised practice to frame additional rooms and to construct and install doors and windows.

## **Mathnasium,** Math Tutor | Pensacola, FL / Remote

## September 2020 - November 2021

- Met with hundreds of K-12 students on a semi-weekly (2-4 sessions per week per student), improving test scores for 90+ students.
- Designed practice problems catered to each student, improving math literacy and alleviating stress related to math difficulties.
- Used the Socratic method to foster critical thinking, independent reflections, and to increase mastery of arithmetic functions, basic geometry, algebra, and calculus.

## **EDUCATION**

## **GENERAL ASSEMBLY | REMOTE**

Software Engineering Immersive

May 2021 - July 2021

### ST. JOHN'S COLLEGE | SANTA FE, NM

Bachelor's of Arts in (Philosophy & History of Science and Mathematics), (Comparative Lit. & Classics)

May 2021